( Crunch )
( Highest girl ) Come on , slow poke !
Don 't lean forward ! Don 't lean forward !
( Laughing )
( Man ) Come on , Overman . Give us a break , will you ?
Look at the clown in the jockey shorts !
Kelly , come on . Pay attention .
Hey , girls !
Do it like this ! Ooh !
( Man ) Damn it , Kelly ! Do the job !
Next time we 're goin ' right into the lagoon .
The lagoon is my favourite ! ( Laughs )
Damn boat . I flooded the ... Damn boat !
( Girl ) Come on , Richie . I got a date tonight !
( Skier ) Through the gate !
( Richie ) Come on , baby .
OK , guys , here we go .
Oh ! That 's right . Good .
( Woman ) You 've been chosen for your neatness ,
courtesy toward others and your Southern grace .
We enforce our dress code here , so keep your hair and nails trimmed .
And , please , don 't alter your costumes .
Once you 've got your Sea World guide apparel ,
the shorts are short enough .
( Girl giggles )
Show any cheek and you 'll be back shovellin ' french fries .
( Girls giggling )
Now , let 's continue with our welcome speech again . All together now .
( All ) Welcome to Sea World ,
the world 's largest marine life park .
Above and below the surface of our unique Undersea Kingdom ...
( Man ) The park opens on Saturday .
All this week has been , and continues to be , preview week ,
during which family and friends attend Sea World as our guests .
This is the Undersea Kingdom ,
four years under construction , at a cost of more than $ 34 million .
Four pressurised viewing tunnels radiate out into the lagoon .
There 's the Sunken Spanish Galleon , Jonah 's Marine Fun House ,
the Deepwater Coral Forest , all connected to Central Control .
And a deluxe restaurant and lounge , all 4O feet below the surface .
The complex is built in our manmade lagoon ,
which connects to the ocean by a deep channel .
The new additions to Sea World are the brainchild
of entrepreneur Calvin Bouchard .
( Kelly ) Hi , guys !
( Girl ) Now you can close the gate .
( Gate motor whirring )
( Thud )
( Man ) Jesus !
Overman , I thought you said those tracks were secure .
Hey , I welded the damn thing myself .
( Worker ) Something 's hung the gate up .
( 2nd worker ) Better get Brody . He 'll be pissed .
Whoo !
( Guy ) Here 's the lagoon . Set up for the turn .
( PR man ) I call your attention to the Sea World skiers ,
who are entering the lagoon
in a preview of the opening day ceremonies .
( Reporters chattering , indistinct )
Here come my pride and joy .
( Female reporter ) Can we talk to Mr Bouchard ?
- Beautiful . Just beautiful ! - ( Girl skier ) Hi !
( Man ) ... this exciting complex .
We WOULD like to avoid references to his colourful past .
( Woman ) Did the Undersea Kingdom really cost $ 30 million ?
Aren 't those kids great ?
Mr Bouchard , is there anything special goin ' on openin ' day ?
Well , this afternoon , at the main gate , we 'll be pleased to announce ...
the welcomin ' of Mr Philip FitzRoyce .
Oh , really ? Is that true ?
No lie , he gonna be here . Now , we got drinks at the bar .
They free . Come on , follow me .
( Reporters laugh )
- What 's it look like ? - It 's off the track .
- How 'd that happen ? - I can 't tell , but she is jammed .
Just wouldn 't close , Mike .
( Overman ) Now what do we do ?
Somethin ' knocked the son-of-a-bitch right off the track .
Just secure the damn gate , all right ?
- Think you can handle that ? - On overtime , maybe .
You got enough overtime .
- Your party . - You buy the beer , Brody .
Well , look , you 're in charge .
See you guys later . I got more important things to do .
- No overtime . - OK . See you , Mike .
( Shouting ) No overtime !
( All shouting , laughing ) No overtime !
( Dolphins clicking )
( Clicking loudly )
( Clicking continues )
( Dolphins clicking , cage rattling )
Hi , Mike .
- Oh . Ah . Hey , Dan . - Hey .
Havin ' gate problems ?
The dolphins tried to open them again .
- Where 's the boss ? - Up with Shamu .
Thanks .
( Woman ) Come on , Cindy .
Come on , Sandy . Come on .
- Hey , Liz . - Hey . Come on .
It 's the boss hard hat . Where 's your boots ?
I only wear ' em to bed and in the shower .
- Where 's Kay ? - She 's down that way .
Yee-hah ! Ride ' em , cowgirl .
- Hi , Mike ! - Hey !
- I 'll be with you in a minute . - All right .
Use your spurs .
Hey , Liz !
Good boy . That was nice !
- Hey . - Hey !
Liz , he did that great . I don 't wanna do it again . Do me a favour .
Put Cindy and Sandy in the lagoon for a run .
OK .
- How you doin ' ? - Great .
Hey , you . Come here .
( Shamu squeaks )
Come here , kiddo . That 's the feeding place .
- Is this whale house-broken yet ? - Nope .
- Then he can 't come to dinner . - You takin ' me to dinner ?
Soon as we pick up my brother .
When 's Sean coming ?
We 're gonna meet him at the main gate .
( Dan ) Kathy .
Cindy and Sandy don 't wanna go .
Am I gonna lose you to a couple of neurotic fish ?
- Mammals . - Mammals . Mammals .
( Dan ) Something 's bugging ' em .
It 's play time . They 'll be beggin ' us tomorrow . Put ' em up .
You got it .
- I 'm begging you tonight . - You don 't have to beg .
Take me to dinner !
All right . Let 's try sushi .
- Mike ! - I 'll change .
Come here . Who 's a good boy ?
Are you a good boy ? Yes , you 're a good boy .
( Shamu gurgles )
And you get a fish .
( Calvin ) Ladies and gentlemen , here he is now .
Ladies and gentlemen , Mr Philip FitzRoyce , with a capital R ,
is here to film us , meet our resident day scientific staff .
- Hey , what 's this ? - Oh , no .
Philip the Great .
I am able to combine business with pleasure ,
which , they tell me , is the secret to a long and happy life .
- What , FitzRoyce ? - Mmm .
Sure is .
Any further questions , in the bar , if you please .
For the first one who buys .
- Look at Calvin . Best of buddies . - Ah , best of friends .
( Mike ) A regular Barnum and Bailey .
( Kay ) I 'm sure they 'll be very happy together .
Perfect . Into the Undersea Kingdom they go .
( Chuckle )
Hey , Mikey !
- Hey , hey ! Hey ! - Oh !
- How you doin ' ? - All right !
- My brother , the cowboy . - Hey ! Hug me , huh ?
- Oh , OK . - Hey .
( Kay shrieks )
You put on weight , you need a shave and you 're too tall .
Well , two out of three I can fix .
( Laughs ) Get that gear and let 's go . Come on .
- So , nice boots . - Thanks ! Aw , gee .
How 'd you do on your finals ?
Great . A gentleman 's " C , " an incomplete , but I aced Phys Ed .
- ( Kay ) A real Einstein . - Glad you 're here .
( Thud )
There you go , Charlene .
- ( Man ) Shelby showed up yet ? - ( 2nd man ) Haven 't seen him .
( Woman ) What are they doing ?
( Man ) Kelly 's really gettin ' this one down .
( Woman ) See that big guy ? He gets knocked on his ass every time .
( Woman laughs )
- All right , Charlene . - All right !
Here , let me help you out . Work with me , work with me .
Let 's go .
- There we go . - Wait . One more .
- Hey , Mike . - All right . Yeah ?
Is Shelby workin ' overtime ?
Not on my say-so . He was supposed to knock off .
Have you met my kid brother ?
If he 's messin ' with that bitch at the souvenir stand ,
it 's gonna be his ass .
- You tell him . - Charlene , I 'm not his mother .
- You 're his boss . - Yeah , ask Woodbury , OK ?
( Man ) Come on , Kelly . You can do it !
- They 're playing stand-off . - Uh-oh .
My brother considers himself the stand-off champion of New England .
And the western states .
- Go get ' em . - ( Growls )
( Whooping , laughter )
Hey , I wasn 't ready !
I tell you , it 's a game of balance . I told you he 'd fall on his ass .
( Man ) Hey , who 's this guy ?
This is for beers . You buyin ' ?
Ready ?
My fly 's open . ( Chuckles )
( Bystanders gasping )
- No fair ! - ( Guy ) Whooo !
Well , it 's , uh ...
not only a game of balance , it 's a game of deception .
Come on , I 'll buy you two and the one you owe me .
- OK . - All right .
( Bystander ) All right . ( Girl ) See you later , Kelly .
Hey , I want you . Come on , right now ! Let 's go .
- Kathryn , Mike . - ( Mike ) Hi .
- You know each other ? - I see my brother nailed you .
- Your brother ? - Yeah .
Without that old crotch trick , he 'd never have won .
- That 's his best move . - Runs in the family .
Well , it worked .
- What are we drinkin ' ? - Champagne of the working classes .
- Beer . You owe me a couple . - That 's right . Comin ' up .
Two beers . So , you work at the park , huh ?
- Mm-hmm . I 'm a water skier . - Oh .
( Laughs ) Your brother 's cute .
Yeah . Him and Kathryn have , uh , been together for a year and a half .
How about you ?
Desperately unattached .
Lonely , confused .
Generous and loving to a fault . It 's all in my eyes .
( Man ) Come on . ( 2nd man ) OK .
We 'll cop a lot of good stuff tonight .
- I 've got the tanks . - Shh !
- Is the van OK here ? - Yes , it 's OK .
We 're off Sea World property . Nobody uses this road .
Shh !
Yeah .
Climb over the fence , and take it easy with the raft .
( Clatter )
( Whispering ) Damn it !
You asshole .
Now we gotta drag it all the way down to the water !
- Ready to go ? - OK . Who 's payin ' ?
Ah .
- Watch out . Snakes . - Oh , come on . Don 't bullshit me .
Chicken , huh ?
- ( Croaks ) - ( Man gasps )
All right , steady .
- Steady . - Got it .
OK . Here we go .
- Come on , paddle ! - I am .
Let 's go out to the centre .
I sure hope this is worth it .
- ( Laughing ) - ( Mike groaning )
- Hey , Kelly , is this your car ? - Sure is .
Hey . Get off of there !
( Moaning , groaning )
- You wanna take a walk ? - Yeah .
Hey , what about baby brother ?
- Aww ! - Aww !
Little baby brother .
Kelly , can you give him a ride home , or shall I call his mommy ?
- Nah , if he 'll come quietly . - No way . I scream and shout .
Oh , God , it stinks out here . Let 's get away !
- See ya . - Hey , let 's go swimming .
- N-no , I hate the ocean . - Aww ! Hey , I 've got a better idea .
- Like lagoons ? - Lagoons ?
- Lagoons . - ( She laughs )
( Engine starts )
Oh . How come Sean doesn 't visit more ?
- He hates the water . - What ?
Yeah . Remember that shark attack I told you about when we were in Amity ?
Well , that 's why he goes to school in Colorado .
If our parents didn 't live on an island , he 'd never get wet .
- ( She laughs ) - My dad , he 's the same way .
God , I love this place .
I hated it when we first came here .
What 's the matter ?
Did you get a telephone call ?
Venezuela ?
Guess I 'm gonna have to start learning Spanish .
- Ooh , baby . - Yeah . Yeah .
That 's wonderful . That 's wonderful .
Oh , shit .
Reality .
How long ?
Just a short year and a half .
I 'd love you to come , you know .
Yeah .
But what about the six months I 've got left here
and the job opening up at the Scripps Institute ?
What about that ? Huh ?
Simple . Just give up your life and follow me .
( She laughs )
- Oh , I 'm happy for you . I am . - I know you are .
What are we gonna do ?
- Aha . - Mm-hmm .
( Both chuckling )
- Ooh ! - ( Laughs )
( Chuckles )
Come on .
- Oh , I don 't go in the water . - You don 't swim ?
Not even with friends ?
Oh , uh , I swim . I just , uh , I ... I ...
( Sighs ) It 's something that happened when I was a kid .
I don 't go in the water . ( Laughs awkwardly )
Hmm .
I bet I can overcome your childhood fears .
I bet you can .
Come on .
My boots !
Kick ' em off , cowboy .
- Kelly ! - Come on in , Sean . It 's fun .
Come on .
- Here ? - Yeah , OK .
Somewhere down there is the best coral .
A guy in Miami will give us $ 200 for the good stuff .
Put it in the basket . I 'll pull it up .
( Kelly laughing in distance )
Come on , hurry , Randy .
I love this park at night . It 's so deserted .
Yeah . So quiet .
Wait a second . Isn 't that Kelly 's car ?
Stop , stop , stop . Shh ! Wait a second .
Stop .
Shh .
( Giggling )
I don 't believe it .
She got him in the water .
Never underestimate the power , huh ?
Attention . You , in the water . You are trespassing on Sea World property .
Come out of the water with your hands raised high above your head .
I 'm OK . My brother works here .
Uh , I 'm Kelly Ann Bukowski , from the ski team .
You turkeys have any ID ?
Wait a minute .
- Mike ? Kay ? - Brother ?
Mr Bullhorn sees all , knows all !
Dead is what you are !
You keep your hands to yourself , young m ...
- ( Kelly screeches ) - Here , take this .
( Mike ) Yell for mother !
( Mike , Sean shouting , indistinct )
Finish up down there , damn it !
Come on , Randy . We gotta get outta here !
- ( Muffled thud ) - Now what ?
Ow !
( Shouts )
( Kelly ) Mike !
( Girls screeching )
( Kelly yelling , indistinct )
( Yelling , screaming )
- ( Kay ) You cheater ! - ( Screams )
( Sean ) That 's what you are ! Dead !
Some guys can sleep in in the morning .
Some of us have to be at work early . Good morning .
Some of us don 't have to baby-sit a park full of slugs and fishes either .
Yes , we just live like slugs and fishes .
The dog does not eat on the counter .
( Groans ) I put your wet clothes in the dryer , sweetie .
- Thanks . - Mmm . What are we eating ?
Mmm . Thank you .
Hey , is this my beeper or your beeper ?
- I dunno . I 'll use this beeper . - Use that beeper .
Talk to you later .
I 'll have my beeper beep your beeper .
I 'll have my beeper beep your beeper back .
- Bye . - See you later .
Aye .
Coffee ?
Just throw it in my eyes , it 'll work faster .
That 's what happens when you stay up all night
workin ' out childhood phobias .
That 's right . Make fun of your baby brother .
I was this close to doing it in the water last night ,
and that 's a first .
- This close , huh ? - Shut up !
( Laughs )
Sorry . I didn 't know it was therapy .
Just admit it . You messed me up .
I admit it . I messed you up .
Is everything all right with you and Kathryn ?
( Phone )
Hello ? Yes , sir .
Calvin , I had my crew on that yesterday .
Well , I know . I don 't want that to happen either .
( Sighs ) Tomorrow .
OK , OK . Calvin , I 'll be right there .
- The boss , right ? - I gotta go to work .
- Yeah , can 't do better than that ! - Really .
( Squeaking )
Yeah . Yeah !
Who 's a good girl ? That 's my baby .
( Dan ) Kay ?
( Kay ) How are Cindy and Sandy ?
Well , Cindy 's OK , but Sandy 's still nervous .
( Kay ) Don 't quit , Danny . He can go higher .
( Kay ) That 's it !
OK , girls . There are my girls .
Thank you . Come on . Ready ... and go !
That 's it .
What is this ? You ready ? I said go !
If those are the best behaviours , I 'd hate to see the worst .
May I help you ?
Are you looking for somebody ?
No , I don 't think you can . I 'm looking for someone in authority .
Well , I 'm Dr Morgan , the senior biologist .
Oh .
Really ?
Charming . Philip FitzRoyce .
I know you . I know your work .
We were at that Law of the Sea Conference together last summer .
Right . Helsinki . Save the Whales .
They made a hero out of me .
You know what I never understood ? Why did you ram that Japanese whaler ?
( Chuckles ) Because he got in my way , ruined my best shot .
Yeah . I was impressed .
Good . Then perhaps we can have a drink and some dinner tonight ?
Oh , I 'm sorry , Mr FitzRoyce , but ... that 's a behaviour I just don 't do .
Nice spins , Danny . I 'll meet you at the holding tank .
Hey , aqua girl !
- Hi , Mike ! - Five .
( Grunts )
He don 't sleep in , he don 't live in .
Tell Shelby Overman he can take a flyin ' leap
at a rollin ' doughnut on a gravel driveway , you hear ?
Hold it . Didn 't he come home last night ?
- No . - He didn 't show up here either .
- I figure he 's home hung over . - I don 't want him around my place !
He 's gone . You take his stuff .
Charlene , what 's goin ' on , huh ?
- Shelby Overman 's AWOL again . - Oh , no . I 'm sorry .
- What , is this all his stuff ? - Yeah . Doesn 't figure .
He left his passport and his ... and his credit cards .
Driver 's licence , pawn tickets .
I don 't think he could have been planning to go too far .
You don 't think something happened to him ?
No . No , look . He is curled up , drunk someplace .
When I find him , he 's in deep trouble .
We 'll let you know as soon as we hear anything .
- Wanna help me out ? - Yeah . Take care , Charlene .
- Help me look in the lagoon ? - You bet .
Hey , I 'm mad at that old boy , but I don 't mean him any harm .
You hear me ? I don 't mean him any harm !
Down a little more .
Turn it .
Batteries are fully charged , Mike .
- Thank you , Danny . - Thanks , Danny .
Control room , submersible is now entering the lagoon .
- Roger . - I can monitor it from here .
( Technician ) ' Testing , one , two , three . Can you read me , Kay ? '
( Kay ) ' I read you . Communication 's fine .
' For Charlene 's sake , I sure hope he 's all right . '
( Mike ) ' There 's Cindy ... or Sandy ? I don 't know how to tell them apart . '
( Kay ) ' Cindy 's a lot larger . '
( Mike ) ' Control , this is Venture One .
' We 're at 25 feet , headed for the Spanish Galleon . '
I can see you now . Hi , Mike .
' Overman broke divers ' rules last night , out there .
' Went down to shackle the sea gate alone .
' Lf anything happened , the current would have washed him up here ,
' toward the centre of the lagoon . '
( Kay ) ' What about the filtration pipes ? '
' It 's too strong a current the other way .
' The flow 's all into the lagoon .
' There 's a million gallons of fresh salt water every hour . '
( Kay ) ' Could he be trapped in the Spanish Galleon ? '
( Mike ) ' The superstructure could have kept him from floating . '
( Kay ) ' Mike ! Oh , God . For a second I thought ... '
( Mike ) ' Yeah , yeah . I know it . We call him Oscar .
' You stay here , Kay . I 'll go into the galleon for a closer look . '
' Uh-uh , I 'm goin ' with you . '
( Mike ) ' Goddamn dolphins ! What the hell are they doing ? '
' I don 't know . They 've been acting strange for days . Look at ' em . '
( Kay ) ' Control , we 're leaving the sub .
- ' We 'll be out of radio contact . ' - OK , Dr Morgan .
' Grab your ABS bottles , Kay . Let 's go . '
' OK , sweetie . '
( Squeaks excitedly )
( Squeaks )
( Muffled scream )
( Muffled exchange )
( Mike , Kay , muffled ) ' Go ! Go ! '
( Kay ) Mike ! Quick ! Mike !
- The gate ! Get the gate ! - Shark !
- God ! - What 's happening ?
( Dan ) Close , damn it ! Close !
Shit !
- Oh , God ! Are you OK ? - What the hell was that ?
- Yeah ! What is that ? - You OK ?
My guv 'nor 's the 16th Earl of Haddenfield .
Shake hands with the first Calvin of Sea World .
- Enchanté . - He know French too , huh ?
Excuse me , Mr Bouchard ...
Wait a minute . We 're havin ' dinner here .
- This better be important . - It is , sir .
( Whispers ) Mike and Dr Morgan were pursued by a shark .
It is important . Come with me .
( Kay ) Calvin , it was a great white .
Ten feet long , exhibiting a typical feeding pattern .
On us , Calvin ! The damn thing tried to feed on us .
- Where is it ? - Right here .
- Huh ? - ( Whistles )
You know , Cal , this could be a stroke of luck .
If we kill this beastie on camera ...
I can guarantee you media coverage .
Lure him into a staging area ,
and at the precise moment , slit his belly wide open .
- Can you do that ? - You try and stop ' im , mate .
( Chuckles ) That 's how we earn our bread .
Well , Jack is oversimplifying matters , as is usual .
But ... yeah , I can do that .
( Kay ) No ! ( Mike ) No ?
What do you mean , no ?
I don 't know if it 's occurred to any of you-all ,
but there isn 't a great white alive in captivity anywhere .
Now , we 're unique here , Calvin , you know that .
If any facility can maintain a white , it 's us .
If we could dart him , w-we could get him in a holding tank ...
Hold it ! This is crazy , this is nuts .
White sharks are killers . I know ' em .
My father , my brother , myself .
They 're murderers . No , Kay .
Calvin , they die magnificently .
( Laughs )
That would really be a spectacular event . No doubt about that , huh ?
What are we doing , Calvin , planning a network special ?
We could be the first people on the planet to have a great white alive .
Not if my guv 'nor gets it first , miss .
OK . Say he kills it . Well , that 's it .
It 's one shot , over , gone .
But a live great white ... You think about that , Calvin !
Nightly bulletins on the progress of the killer shark .
Pictures of us nursing it back to health
and lowering it into a holding tank .
Now , that 's world news !
Think of the lines at the gate .
Then you miss the sport of the kill .
Now , wait up , Jack . Wait up .
( Philip ) Killing is guaranteed press .
But this other is much , much more interesting .
OK , this is MS-2-22 .
This is quinaldine , but I had to guesstimate the dosage .
- Kathy ? - Right . Thanks , Danny .
All right , we 're ready in Control . You all set ?
' We 're ready down here . '
( Kay clears throat )
With those TV monitors rolling ,
you 're gonna have more coverage than a space launch .
Good . Just the way I like it .
The colour of your wet suit 's one hell of a choice .
- The shark 's gonna love you . - Exactly .
- It helps me get the close-ups . - You 're the showman .
Honey , is this suit gonna protect you ?
Have you felt ?
It won 't bite through , but it will yield to pressure .
So she might just get a little ... squeeze .
Oh , that 's great news . Look , why do you have to do this ?
Why don 't you let Her Majesty 's number one son take care of it ?
Because it 's my job , remember ?
Yeah , but I just don 't want it to be you .
You build the stuff , I swim around in it . That was the deal . Right ?
Hmm ?
I love you , too .
If we get into any trouble , all we have to do is pull the pin .
- What are those ? - ( Jack ) Mills bombs .
- What ? - Mills bombs , sonny .
Grenades . A chap in Her Majesty 's ordinance makes them up for me .
( Philip ) ' Baby claymores . Good dispersion .
' Some concussion but they do the trick . '
Well , not in my water . Take ' em off .
You tend to your knitting , my dear , and I tend to mine .
( Mike ) Hold on a second there .
There 's no explosives underwater .
There 's acrylic down there , a very fragile environment . No bombs .
( Philip ) ' Brody , this is insur ... '
( Mike ) ' No , I don 't think you understood me !
' I built this park , and I 'm not gonna see some visiting fireman blow it up
' because he wants to kill a fish ! '
Calvin , are you listening to all this ?
No grenades .
For Christ 's sake , guv 'nor . Remember Australia ?
Oh , don 't worry , Jack . After all , it 's only a little fish .
Son of a ...
The pin has to be pulled .
Right . Get rid of this stuff . Everybody aboard here ? Let 's go .
Shove off .
( Kay ) ' I need one clean belly shot .
' Lf I miss , I 'm gonna have to reload and hope I get him with the second . '
( Philip ) This is a good place to start .
( Engines stop )
( Mike ) Hit the lights .
Shall we dance ?
Why not ? I 'm beginning to feel like King Richard going to the Crusades .
( Philip ) Ready , Jack ? Get the gear .
( Jack ) Brown bread , guv 'nor .
You all right ?
Good luck .
You only get one shot .
( Mike ) Yeah , I know . I know .
( Mike exhales )
What about Kathryn ?
It 'll stick in the shark . Hit her , and it 'll go right through .
Just buoy him up , slow him down , right ?
Dorsal fin , middle of the back .
Seen anything yet ?
We 'll get him on the monitors .
( Kay grunting )
( Kay screams )
Quick ! Mike , He 's making a run !
Quick , shoot him !
( Philip ) He 's getting away !
Damn it !
( Mike ) Get outta the way , Kay !
( Kay ) Now !
Come on .
Right . There you go .
You did it , baby .
Here 's the ladder . Hold on .
Come on . Give me your fins .
- Give me your fins . - Let 's go !
( Dan ) Up you go .
You all right ?
( Gasps )
- Close one . - ( Mike ) Get this stuff off her .
- ( Liz ) That was great ! - What am I , a bloody porter ?
- How about a hand with this ? - First things first .
- Mustn 't ignore the ladies . - Don 't ignore the help .
( Mike ) Looked hairy down there . ( Liz ) You OK ? I was worried .
You sure know how to scare the hell outta me .
Be sure he 's wrapped , OK ? Keep him wet . Let 's get him in a tank .
( Calvin ) ' Film all right ? TV picture looked cloudy . '
Calvin . Kathryn 's fine , Philip is fine , Jack is fine .
' Dan and Liz are fine . I am OK too . '
But ... is the film OK ?
It 's absolutely first-rate , Cal .
You 'll be very happy .
Is everyone OK ? It did look pretty dangerous down there .
It looked pretty dangerous from down here too , Calvin .
( Kay ) We may have to work him all night , keep him moving .
Down , Danny . Down , down . That 's it .
Be sure the oxygen keeps running through his gills .
We don 't wanna lose him .
( Door opens )
Close the door ! Whoever you are , this is off limits .
Liz , uh , get the hose running . I wanna try aerating him , OK ?
( Door closes )
Even to me , the fearless harpoonist ?
Nah , you 're OK .
Come on in , sailor . Are you new in town ?
Yeah . Came by to get me a woman and a tattoo .
- Wanna see the tattoo ? - ( Chuckles )
Well , I 'd rather see the woman , get a look at the competition .
There isn 't any other woman , there isn 't any tattoo either .
I 'm lonely .
- I 'm sorry , darlin ' . - Damn mammal .
This one 's a fish .
A simple , beautiful fish .
OK .
Mike ! Mike ! What are you doing ? Are you crazy ?
- Liz , take a hike . - OK .
If this is the only way we can be together ,
this is the only way we can ... be together .
Welcome aboard , sailor . Get that hose and hold onto it .
- Yeah . OK . - Open the mouth .
Say " hi " to your new friend .
This is the first time you 've ever done my work with me .
Yeah , well , it 's a real thrill .
Maybe tomorrow you can work with me and help me pour foundations .
( Laughs , screams )
Get away ! Get clear ! Get clear !
Didn 't he give you any signs ?
No ! One minute he was dead out , the next he was wide awake !
( Kay ) No food . No medication .
It 's the only live one in captivity , guys . Let 's keep him that way .
Huh ? Don 't do anything that 's gonna traumatise him .
( Applause )
( Woman on PA ) ' Welcome to the opening of the Undersea Kingdom .
' The magical mysteries of Jonah and the Whale , the Coral Forest
' and the Sunken Spanish Galleon . '
Gotcha , guv 'nor .
( Calvin ) It 's a whale with a brain larger than most folks ,
able to earn beaucoup bucks .
Kay and I went down in the sub , and we searched over all this area
before the sharks hit us .
What if Overman went down on the other side ?
The tide might have pulled him out , but his body should have shown up .
Brody , did you check the filtration pipe ?
No , the current 's too strong goin ' the other way .
We got a million gallons of sea water flowing into the lagoon every hour .
The man 's irresponsible . When he turns up , fire him .
Hold it , Calvin . He 's a good man . He just messes up once in awhile .
I 'm gonna hold you responsible .
( Man on PA ) ' She gets to ski by herself , because she 's the best . '
- How 's it doin ' ? - I just got our first printout .
Our advance sales are three times ahead of our other parks .
Not unexpected . Where 's the great white ?
- In the tank room . - Put him in pool six .
Tell people to put that information on welcomes , rest stops and wrap-ups .
I thought we were to wait on Dr Morgan 's word .
Look . I run the park , I sell the tickets and I make the decisions .
Move the fish !
I wanna be able to stand in line to see it before three .
... three and down , and up , and turn .
( Whooping )
( PA ) ' The Sea World water ski team
' in a dazzling display of coordination and brilliance .
' The Silver Bullets ! '
- All right ! - Lookin ' good !
There they go !
Yeah ! The helicopters !
Hi , Sean . You were real hot .
I want some time for us alone . You got a few minutes ?
- You bet . - Great , Kelly .
Listen . Ready for some fun ?
Fantastic ! Let 's ride the bumper boats .
Bumper boats ?
This is the entrance to the Undersea Kingdom ,
a complex of underwater tunnels that show you first-hand
the miracles of the deep .
There 's no extra charge for this unique attraction .
Our underwater tunnels are not only fun , but informative .
Oh , look at that .
( PA ) ' Consumed alive in history , Jonah found out what it was like
' to live in the belly of the ocean 's greatest animal .
' Our special Jonah and the Whale showcase is at 11 : 00 , 1 : 00 and 4 : 00
' in the amphitheatre inside the Undersea Kingdom . '
( Hissing )
( Mechanical voice ) Ha-ha-ha-ha . This is Captain Sink .
Welcome to my cave of fun and surprises .
( Girls ) Oh , yuck !
( Mike laughs ) I sure am gonna miss these guys .
How ' bout it , Casper ?
You wanna take the money and run to Venezuela with old Mikey ?
- ¿ Quieres un pescado ? - You speak Spanish ?
( Laughs )
( Sighs ) I think they 're gonna miss you , too .
Now you and I are gonna have to have a serious conversation sometime ...
about what 's really goin ' on .
You and me .
I know . I know .
( PA ) ' Mike Brody . Mike Brody . Call your office , please . '
See ya later .
( PA ) ' Sea World , in honour of opening day ... '
Oh , Casper .
What 's a girl to do , huh ?
Thank you .
' ... a great white shark in holding pool number six .
' You will be able to view the one and only great white in captivity . '
( PA ) ' The great white shark 's roamed the ocean for millions of years .
' A proud animal ... '
Excuse me . Oh , God !
' ... while alone , is a predator ... '
Excuse me ! What is he doing here ?
Calvin ordered him moved .
Why didn 't he ask me ? Why did he go ahead on his own ?
( PA ) ' This shark , a first of its kind to be held ... '
No , Danny ! Danny !
Liz , get a hose ready , I wanna aerate him now !
Come on , Danny . Get the back .
( PA ) ' Please , uh , remain calm .
' That 's Dr Morgan and assistant members of our staff .
' Uh , please don 't interfere in any way . '
Excuse me .
( Kay ) Liz ! Liz !
Come on , boy .
That 's it . Come on .
Turn it , Danny .
- Shit ! - Come on . Come on !
No . Boy , come on !
Excuse me .
( PA ) ' Let me bring your attention to some other events ... '
( Philip ) Kathryn .
' ... the seal and otter show and of course ... '
Kathryn .
Bad luck .
( Sighs )
Go ahead .
Photograph it .
- Look out ! - Kelly . Kelly .
I don 't know . L-I don 't ... No . No .
Come on , you 'll love it . It 's fun . Trust me . Come on !
What is this thing ? L-I ... Are you sure ?
Are you sure we should be doing this ?
Oh ! Oh , God .
Can this hold two people ?
Oh . Push . Push .
Oh , my God . Are you steering this , or am I ?
( People laughing , chattering )
Go ! Go ! Get away ! Get away !
( PA ) ' We invite you to enter the magical world of the Coral Forest
' where you may observe the wonders of the deep without ever getting wet .
' The Spanish Galleon plays host to many colourful fish
' that we have assembled from the different oceans of the world . '
- Look at all of them ! - Oh , yeah !
( Girl ) That looks like a butterfly . ( 2nd Girl ) You 're right .
( Man ) Oh , my God ! Look at that !
Kay , you don 't want to see this .
Everybody is assuming this was a shark attack .
- Now , I wanna make sure . - OK . All right .
Did you guys pull him out ?
( Mike gasps )
That 's Shelby Overman .
- Kay , I told ... - Miss ...
Mike . Ray .
If this was a shark attack , I 've seen it before .
OK ?
Oh , Mike .
Oh , my God !
Let 's go find Calvin . Come on ! Come on !
( Man ) I 'm getting contradictory readings from the filtration pumps .
( Leonard ) Such as ? - High pump rate , low outflow
and a pressure build-up on the inboard tunnel valve .
- That 's number two . - Could be an obstruction .
Well , that 's not my department .
See if you can locate Brody or Calvin , will you ?
( Calvin ) Very posh .
Yes , it 's quite a display .
Tell me . How do you contain the sharks in this part of the lagoon ?
It 's that old shark screen , that bubble screen .
You know , sharks don 't like that .
It 's what they call , uh ... marine segregation .
Dr Bouchard . Telephone .
Ah , excuse me , gentlemen . Be comfortable now .
Here you go , sir .
Bouchard here .
What about the pumps ?
Ah , nah , nah , nah . Don 't wait for Brody .
Just , uh ... shut down number two pump and switch over to number one .
Simple as that .
Because it costs too much to replace and they burn out !
Tell Brody to get down here to the Neptune Room on the double !
- Thank you . - ( Man ) You 're welcome .
Well , gentlemen .
Chin-chin .
- Oh , cheers . - Cheers .
( Kay ) There they are .
- Calvin , I 've got bad news . - Keep your voices down , sit down .
Sit down !
Was it the shark ?
It was a shark .
with a bite radius about a yard across .
Don 't be silly . That would indicate a shark of some 35 feet in length .
You said it exactly .
- Our shark still has all its teeth . - Yeah .
That means it was a baby .
Our shark couldn 't have killed Overman .
Its mother did .
You talkin ' about some damn shark 's mother ?
Don 't you hear what she 's sayin ' ?
I 'm listening !
Well , she gave birth way out to sea , and the baby swam
through the sea gate that you left open , Brody !
No ! Overman was killed inside the park .
The baby was caught inside the park .
Its mother is inside the park .
( Echoing ) She 's right there !
( Screaming )
( Woman ) How did that thing get in there ?
- The animals are in the lagoon ! - Ski show !
Control , this is Bouchard . Listen carefully !
Clear the tunnel , let the people out , close the gate and seal the park !
Seal the park ! I 'll be down in a minute .
( Man ) Hey ! Hey ! Watch it !
( Woman ) Who is that guy ? ( Man ) Watch out !
Hey , bring it over here ! Hey !
All right . I 've had enough fun . Let 's go in now .
Come on . You 're enjoying this .
No . Look , don 't you have to be at work or something ?
I don 't have to be back till the second half .
- Oh . - Come on .
Gotcha , lovers .
- Shit ! - God .
- Get out ! Get out ! - Hey , what the ? !
Hey , what are ya doin ' ? !
Brody !
Get out of the water . Get out !
Get out of the water , please . Please , come in from the water .
Out of the water ! Come on ! Get out of the water !
Out of the water !
Get out !
Get outta the way !
Shit !
( Man ) This is Sea World Control .
Uh-huh .
Yes . I got him right here .
( PA ) ' All right , boys . Come take a bow .
' I apologise to have you ... No ! Get up here ! '
Get outta the water ! Get outta the water !
( Announcer ) Boys . Boys !
Bring the boat in ! Get outta the water !
You 're gonna get both of us fired out here !
Get out ! Everybody out !
Gimme the mike !
Hey , Brody ! Come back here !
Get outta the water !
Bring it in .
Bring the boat in ! Get outta the water now !
Ready , up ! One . Two .
Bring that boat in ! Get outta the water right now !
Hey , get me down ! Just get me down !
- Get me down ! - What are you saying ?
There 's something back there ! A shark !
Bring your boat in !
There 's a shark !
( Audience screaming )
( Screaming continues )
( Brody on PA ) Get outta the water !
( Girls ) One , two , three , four , five , six , seven .
- Get out ! - Up . Turn .
Oh , my God ! Shark !
( Brody ) Get outta the water !
( Man in boat ) We 're coming ! We 're coming !
It 's gonna eat us !
They 'll die !
- Gimme your hand . Come on ! - Pull me out !
Hang on !
( Sean ) Needs a choke or something . Pull it .
( Both gasp )
( Sean ) Hold my hand .
( Sean ) Kelly !
Shark !
Kelly !
- What the hell is that ? - Shit ! Hang on !
( Girl ) What happened ?
( Girl ) She 's drowning ! She 's drowning !
Swim ! Swim , kid , swim !
( People gasping )
( Philip ) Call an ambulance .
Quickly . Come on . Get out of the way !
Get a paramedic !
Look out , Mommy !
- Did you call an ambulance ? - Yeah , the paramedics .
( Mike ) Twist that tourniquet tight and hold it there .
( Sean ) I 'm here . You 're OK .
( Man ) They 're bringin ' in the wounded . The ambulance is on the way .
Shall I leave the gate open ? Cindy and Sandy are out there .
Shit .
No . They 'll have to take care of themselves .
We can 't take our chance on that big bitch gettin ' in .
- Hey , you all right ? - Yeah . Yeah . Fine .
Uh , I 'm gonna go with Kelly .
I think you should .
- What are you gonna do ? - I don 't know .
Hello out there . This is Calvin Bouchard .
May I please have your kind attention .
Due to technical difficulties ,
it has become necessary for us to temporarily close
the Undersea Kingdom now .
For those of you all still in the underwater portion of this park ,
please follow your guides , and they will point out
the most convenient and accessible exits .
Where the hell is the nearest accessible exit ? We 're underwater !
- Is this off ? - Uh-huh .
- Gimme some lights down there ! - OK .
Can 't see shit down there ! Get me some medical attention , quick !
OK , ladies and gentlemen , please follow me
in an orderly fashion , and remember - walk , do not run .
Daddy , Daddy ! Look at the fish !
- Look ! - Holy shit !
( Panicked screams )
( Screaming )
( Technician ) Tunnel six failure .
It 's Jonah and the Whale .
Tube integrity has been compromised . We 've got leakage and pressure loss .
We have to seal the section or we 'll lose the whole complex .
- Watertight doors . Hit it . - On automatic .
They 're all on go status . Activated . Now !
( People screaming )
I need my wallet !
( Screaming continues )
Quiet ! Quiet ! Please !
I need your attention , please . Quiet !
Now the water is not going any higher , so calm down , OK ?
It 's stopped . It 's stopped , so calm down .
( Guide ) ' The oxygen that we have in here is all we have ,
' so let 's not panic , but let 's try to take shallow breaths , OK ? '
- Hey , Mike . - Yeah !
This is our last cut . I think our tunnel patch is ready to go .
Good . Rig the winch on that work boat up there .
You got it .
- How much longer , sweetie ? - I don 't know .
No ?
We 're gonna have to nudge these tunnel sections together .
Then we 'll patch it and weld the whole thing .
Then we evacuate ?
No , then we put pressure back into the tunnels ,
then the watertight doors will open up , then people go home .
Hey , watch how you 're cuttin ' that . It 's critical !
Relax . You 're doin ' everything you can .
Come on . Come over here .
Listen .
I 've been thinking .
Maybe Venezuela can use some trained whales .
- What ? Are you serious ? - Yeah .
I think this one 's on me .
- But next year ... - I 'll follow you anywhere .
- Yeah ! - I love you !
( Chattering )
Ah , Mr Glass .
Is Mr Bouchard going to be here ?
Please , please . I have a statement to make .
- Was there an explosion ? - How many people are missing ?
Late today , due to a minor disturbance ,
there was a pressure failure in one of the tunnels -
a major attraction at the park .
We estimate that 30 to 40 people
were in the process of being evacuated
when the watertight safety doors temporarily delayed their exit .
We 're working right now to release them
under the safest possible circumstances .
Seven visitors were also injured in our beach area .
- That 's all . Give me a break . - What about a shark ?
- I 'll let you know as I know more . - A very large shark ...
That 's all . There is no more .
( Woman ) When will this be fixed ?
( Guide ) I 'm sure they 're working on it .
Stay together to keep warm . I know you 're cold .
Stay together , take shallow breaths and concentrate on your breathing .
Well , any sign of mother ?
OK , then .
Where did the animal hide the first time ?
Uh ...
filtration pipe .
Opposite side of the lagoon .
Brody , is there an access hatch , a backwash gate ?
Heavy grillwork . Keeps the pumps clear when we back-flush that system .
Why ? What do you want to do ? Get that thing back in ?
He 's a bright lad .
Yes . Jack and I are going to lure him back into the pipe ,
close the gates and then dispose of him at our leisure .
Meanwhile , you can weld your patch and then evacuate the civilians .
What if she doesn 't want to go back in ?
I think we can pretty much guarantee she 'll want to go back in .
- Right , Jack ? - Sure .
Just how are you going to guarantee that ?
Live bait .
( Man ) We 're ready to move out over the tunnel now .
( Mike ) Let 's go .
L-I 'll be in the Control Room .
I 'll go with you .
( Man ) Give me that . I 'll store it over here .
( Man ) No , I got it .
( Technician ) Yeah , we 're on top of it .
OK . Thanks .
Now , where 's that damn fish ?
There . I 've got him .
( Technician ) Sorry , it 's the dolphins .
Babies , stay out of it , please .
... and I 've rigged a lifeline .
Just let the pumps push you out and use the rope to pull yourself back .
Right .
And why don 't I do all the filming ?
I want both cameras . We need the coverage . Come on , Jack !
This isn 't a picnic .
This film is a bloody retirement annuity .
I 'd feel better if you did just the one thing .
( Laughs ) What 's the matter ?
Getting cold feet ?
OK , Bob . Hold it about right there .
- We 're right over the tunnel . - OK , we 're all set .
( Mike ) ' Tell FitzRoyce we 're in position . '
FitzRoyce , you can go now .
( Technician ) They 're testing the lifeline to see if it 's secure .
( Calvin ) ' They 're spreadin ' some chum . You know , fish oil and blood .
' Then Jack 's gonna make some metallic sounds
' to attract her right down into that filtration pipe . '
Start the pumps .
You got it .
( Metal clanging )
( Clanging )
( Technician ) It 's in ! ( Calvin ) He 's got it !
All right . It 's locked .
It 's safe , Brody . Go for it .
OK , let 's go .
( Muffled scream )
( Technician ) ' This is Control . Is that patch in place ? '
Easy .
Let me help you with that , Dr Morgan .
Got it !
Now weld the son-of-a-bitch ...
( Calvin ) Kathryn , what are you doin ' ?
I 'm going down there .
You crazy ?
He needs eyes in the back of his head .
- Thanks , Fred . - All right .
Watch the tanks .
OK .
- Here are your fins . - Thanks .
Be careful down there now .
( Hinges creaking )
( Sighs ) You all right ?
Where 's Mr FitzRoyce ?
I have no idea .
( Man ) What 's goin ' on ?
Guv 'nor !
There 's no other way out ?
You don 't understand . This is it !
Have you looked ?
He didn 't come up .
Guv 'nor , you bloody bastard . Answer me !
We 'll suffocate the bitch . Shut down the pumps .
Are you sure ?
- Why don 't we blow it up ? - Listen , nephew .
A $ 2.5 million turbine 's not going up in smoke cos of a damn fish !
Now shut the pumps down !
( Mechanical whirring )
What 's happened ?
( Man ) They 've shut the pumps off .
( Sighs ) That 's all she needs . The gates can 't hold much longer .
( Sobbing ) Philip , pull the pin ! Pull the pin , Philip .
( Metallic clanking on monitor )
( Clanking )
( Clanking continues )
( Woman ) Look at that !
( Woman ) Jesus !
( Fred ) Oh , my God !
We gotta warn ' em . We gotta tell ' em !
Get ' em up ! It 's coming back . Get ' em up quick !
- Come on ! Hurry up ! - Come on !
Get ' em up !
- Come on , Mike . - Get out of there !
- Come on , Mike ! - ( Calvin ) ' Get ' em up ! '
( Muffled ) Come on !
( Squeaking )
( Muffled ) Pull the door !
How the hell did it get loose ?
Open the hatch !
( Fred ) Come on up , Mike . I gotcha .
Are you all right ?
Do we have pressure in those tunnels yet ?
- Affirmative . - Then get those people out .
Feel the air ! Can you feel the air ?
The water 's going down . The water 's going down !
Try to be calm . Don 't rush to the door .
( Man ) We 're saved !
( All talking and cheering )
( Muffled yelling , crunching )
Oh ! We did it !
The others , Mike . What about the others ?
Calvin made it . Lisa .
Mike . Mike ! The dolphins !
( Kay ) Cindy !
( Mike ) Cindy ! ( Kay ) Sandy !
- Come on ! Cindy ! - Cindy !
Oh , good girl . Sandy !
( Squeaks )
Sandy , come on , baby . Sandy , where are you ?
( Mike ) Sandy !
I hope she made it .
- Cindy , stay . - Sandy .
( Squeaks )
Sandy !
All right !